M. L. Parrish Collection of Victorian Novelists, 1806-1958 (bulk 1830s-1930s ): Finding Aid C0171
Manuscripts Division
- Series 4: Parrish Correspondence, 1913-1944; 39 boxes; 2 items
  - Elkin Mathews, Ltd., 1936-1941; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Maun, Mrs. Barbara, 1933-1937; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Metzdorf, Robert F., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Henry F. Michell C., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Miller, Charles J., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Miller, J. D., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Miller, W., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Mitchell, J. K., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - The Pierpont Morgan Library, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Mott, Howard S., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Moulton, Charles, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Myers & Co., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - N (General), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - National Audubon Society, undated; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Nehrbas, Harold A., undated; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - New York Public Library, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Newton, A. Edward, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Nichols, S. Van B., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Norris, Alfred and Dorothy, undated; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - North, Ernest Dressel, undated; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - O (General), undated; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Old Hickory Bookshop, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Albert Oldach & Son, 1938-1939; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Albert Oldach & Son, 1940-1944; 1 folder (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Ouvry, Mrs, Elinor S., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Pa - Pg (General), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Ph - Pz (General), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Papantonio, Michael, 1936-1939; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Papantonio, Michael, 1940-1941; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Papantonio, Michael, 1942-1943; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Parrish, M. L.: Typewritten drafts of Parrish's autobiographical notes, his Lewis Carroll Oxford memorial proposal, etc.), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Parrish, M. L.: Christmas card list and old cards, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Parrish, M. L.: 70th Birthday, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Parrish, M. L.: Florida trip, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - [no folder], dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Parrish, M. L.: May party, 1941; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Parrish, M. L.: May party, 1942; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Parrish, M. L.: Princeton party, 1941 October 19; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Parrish, M. L.: Stationery orders, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Parrish, M. L.: Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Parrish, M. L.: Photographs (Parrish, his mother and sister), undated; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Parrish, M. L.: Loose material from scrapbook, undated; 1 folder (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Parrish, M. L.: Family correspondence, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Parrish, M. L.: Family correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Parrish, M. L.: Parrish Family Genealogy, undated; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Parrott, T. M., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Patterson, G. S., undated; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Pegasus Book Shop, undated; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Pforzheimer, Arthur, undated; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Philadelphia Club, 1940-1941; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Philadelphia Club, 1942-1943; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Phoenix Book Shop, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Pickering & Chatto Ltd., 1926-1937; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Pickering & Chatto Ltd., 1938-1943; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Pine Valley Golf Club, undated; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Princeton University, 1928-1940; 1 folder (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Princeton University, 1940-1941; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Princeton University, 1942-1944; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Princeton University Library Chronicle, undated; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Publishers' Weekly, undated; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Purdy, Richard L., undated; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Quaritch, Bernard Ltd., 1913-1923; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Quaritch, Bernard Ltd., 1924-1926; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Quaritch, Bernard Ltd, 1927; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Quaritch, Bernard Ltd., 1928; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Quaritch, Bernard Ltd., 1929; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Quaritch, Bernard Ltd., 1930; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Quaritch, Bernard Ltd., 1931-1932; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Quaritch, Bernard Ltd., 1933-1936; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Quaritch, Bernard Ltd., 1937; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Quaritch, Bernard Ltd., 1938-1939; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Quaritch, Bernard Ltd., 1940-1944; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - R (General), undated; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - The Rabbit (Parrish's Dec. 5, 1942 catered club dinner), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - The Rabbit (club), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Randall, David A, 1933-1934; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Randall, David A, 1935; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Randall, David A., 1936; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Randall, David A., 1937-1938; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Randall, David A., 1939-1940; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Randall, David A., 1942-1944; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Randall, David A., 1942-1944; 1 folder (Box 77, Folder 10)
    Note: M. L. Parrish's correspondence with David A. Randall for 1941 is filed under Scribner's, Box 34, folder 3.
  - Random House, Inc., undated; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Ray, Gordon N., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Reade, E. B., undated; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Retz & Storm, Inc., undated; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Richardson, Chesley, undated; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Ridgway, Thomas, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Robert Rivière & Son, Ltd., 1927-1934; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Robert Rivière & Son, Ltd., 1935-1940; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Robinson, William H., Ltd., 1928-1935; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Robinson, William H., Ltd., 1936-1943; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Robson & Co, Ltd., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Rogers, Arthur, 1924-1930; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Rogers, Arthur, 1931-1938; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Rogers, Arthur, 1939-1944; 1 folder (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - The Rosenbach Company, undated; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Rota, Bertram, undated; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Ruder, Barnet B., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Rudge, William Edwin, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Sa - Se (General), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Sh - Sz (General), undated; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Sadleir, Michael, 1924-1929; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Sadleir, Michael, 1930-1932; 1 folder (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Sadleir, Michael, 1933-1934; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Sadleir, Michael, 1935-1938; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Sadleir, Michael, 1939-1944; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Savage, Henry L., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Sawyer, Chas. J., Ltd., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Sayers, Dorothy L., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Scheuer, Alwin J., 1925-1927; 1 folder (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Scheuer, Alwin J., 1928-1932; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Scheuer, Alwin J., 1933-1934; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - The Scribner Book Store, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Sessler, Charles, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - The Shakespere Society of Philadelphia, undated; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Shorter, Clement K., undated; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Show Case, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Smith, Harrison and Helen, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Harry B., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - Smith, Mrs. Isabel M., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Smith, John & Son, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 11)
  - Sotheby & Co., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - Sotheran, Henry, Ltd., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 13)
  - Spencer, Walter T., 1924-1931; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 14)
  - Spencer, Walter T., 1935-1942; 1 folder (Box 81, Folder 15)
  - Spielmann, M. H., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Steedman, Robert D., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Stern, Edward & Company, Inc., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Robert Louis Stevenson (lists), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Robert Louis Stevenson Club, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Stone, Bookshop of Harry, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Stonehill, C. A., Inc., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Swann, Arthur, 1928-1930; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Swann, Arthur, 1931-1934; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - T (General), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Thackeray, W. M. (lists), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Thieme, Evelyn (Mrs. H. P.), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - Thompson Class Club, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - Thorp, Mrs. Margaret F., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Thorp, Willard, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Thorp, Thomas, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - The Times of London, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Tinker, C. B., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Treilhard, Julian G., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Trell, Max, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Trollope, Anthony (lists), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Trotter, Mrs. Elizabeth, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - Charles E. Tuttle Company, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - U - V (General), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - Ulizio, B. George, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - Ulysses Bookshop, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - Union Library Catalogue, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - Van Antwerp, William C., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 15)
  - Van Nosdall, George A., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - van Patten, Nathan, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 17)
  - Varied Thrush (bird), undated; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 18)
  - Victorian Lady Novelists (bibliography by Parrish), undated; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 19)
  - Wa - We (General), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 1A)
  - Edgar H. Wells and Company, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 1B)
  - Wf - Wz (General), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Walmsley, Patricia, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Wanamaker, John and Rodman, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Weaver, Warren, undated; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Weber, Carl J., undated; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Wells, Gabriel, 1923-1934; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Wells, Gabriel, 1935-1943; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Wesleyan University, undated; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Widener Library, Harvard University, undated; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Williams Book Store, undated; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Williams, Sidney Herbert, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Wilmerding, Lucius, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1927-1929; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1930-1931; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1932-1933; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1934-1935; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1936-1937; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1938-1939; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1940-1944; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Winterich, John T., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Wise, Thomas J., undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Wister, Frances A. and Owen, undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Woore, Frank, undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Wormser, Richard S., undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Wroth, Lawrence C., undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - X - Y - Z (General), undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Zanetti, J. Enrique, undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - Zeitlin, Jake, Inc., undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - Zucker, Hyman, undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 13)
  - "Macleod of Dare", 1841-1898; 1 item (Item 147)
    Autograph manuscript, with holograph corrections, of Black's novel MACLEOD OF DARE.
  - "The Martian", 1894-1895; 1 item (Item 148)
    Consists of a partial French manuscript for Du Maurier's THE MARTIAN: early working draft, 5 1/4 pages, in ink on rectos of gray sheets, with numerous revisions. Included is a typed English translation (12 pp.), with inked corrections. THE MARTIAN was Du Maurier's last novel, which was published posthumously (New York, 1897). He was just able to finish correcting proofs before he died; this portion of the manuscript apparently was greatly altered in its final, published form.